Meet Julius Montragon, better known as
Computa [music] on TikTok.
>> Computa, activate Lord Farquaad
sequencing. Computa, make sure this man
feels confident and beautiful on the
inside. [music]
>> Wearing a pair of Meta Ray-Ban glasses,
he approaches total strangers and
programs them as if he's giving
instructions to a computer. And it's
gone totally viral.
>> You're a computer.
>> Yeah, yeah, I'm a computer.
>> No way.
>> Julius is 26. He's from outside Chicago
and now he lives on the south side of
Chicago. He got a pair of Meta Ray-Ban
glasses for Christmas this year and he
started making videos with them in
January and they immediately took off on
TikTok. So far [music] he's been
profiled in the Chicago Tribune and he's
even appeared on Fox 32 in Chicago.
>> And it doesn't work unless you do it
accent and you got to say computer. It
can't be computer.
>> I met Julius when he came to New York
and we went together to a Knicks rally
and I saw firsthand how much the Gen Z
crowd recognizes him. Which brings me to
the glasses. Meta Ray-Bans are genuinely
controversial technology. Critics say
there's real risks to privacy and
there's evidence to back that up. Meta
has said it's considering the
possibility of adding in facial
recognition to the glasses and it even
added a code to the glasses software
although it wasn't enabled and not
possible to use yet. Privacy researchers
have also cautioned that the little
recording light indicator is easy to
miss and cover up. But Computa is
different.
>> You've been programmed, [music] bud.
Hell yeah, love you, bud.
>> Julius told me he never wants to make
anyone feel bad after an interaction.
His videos are silly and the people in
them almost seem to always enjoy them.
That might make Julius one of the few
people who's actually figured out how to
make Meta's technology a use for good or
at least harmless. For more on this
story and to read my interview with
Julius, head over to Business Insider.